Hi everyone, and welcome back.
مرحبًا بكم جميعًا، وأهلًا بكم من جديد.
In this course, you'll be learning how to work with data
في هذه الدورة التدريبية، ستتعلمون كيف تعملون على بيانات
using NumPy, Pandas, and Matplotlib.
باستخدام NumPy وPandas وMatplotlib.
These three packages are essential to your work as a data analyst.
هذه المجموعات الثلاث أساسية لعملكم كمحللي بيانات.
NumPy gives you these awesome data structures called arrays,
يقدم لكم NumPy أبنية البيانات الرائعة هذه، والتي تُسمى مصفوفات
that make working with numeric data super
وتجعل العمل على البيانات الرقمية
simple and faster than what you can do in pure Python.
في غاية السهولة وأسرع مما يمكنكم فعله في لغة Python الخالصة.
NumPy is the foundation for the Python data stack
NumPy هو أساس مخزن بيانات Python،
and it's really what makes Python so great for data analysis.
وهو فعليًا ما يجعل Python لغة شديدة الروعة لتحليل البيانات.
With Pandas, you'll be using data structures called
عند استخدام Pandas، ستستخدمون أبنية بيانات
Data Frames to manipulate and analyze your data.
تُسمى أُطُر بيانات لمعالجة بياناتكم وتحليلها.
Personally, I love working with Pandas,
شخصيًا أحب العمل باستخدام Pandas،
and when you get the hang of it, I think you will too.
وحين تعتادون استخدامه فأعتقد أنكم ستحبونه أيضًا.
And finally, Matplotlib is a package for building visualizations from your data.
وأخيرًا، Matplotlib هي مجموعة لبناء مرئيات من بياناتكم.
You can make many kinds of simple plots with a tiny amount of code,
لا يمكنكم إنشاء عدة أنواع من المخططات البسيطة باستخدام كمّ بسيط من الأكواد فحسب،
but also create professional-looking figures.
بل يمكنكم أيضًا إنشاء رسوم توضيحية ذات مظهر احترافي.
Juno Lee will be leading you through the data analysis process with Python.
ستقودكم جونو لي عبر عملية تحليل البيانات باستخدام لغة Python.
Juno is a data scientist and previously worked at a startup where she
جونو هي عالمة بيانات، عملت سابقًا في شركة مبتدئة حيث مارست
worked on a bunch of machine learning and
العمل على مجموعة من مشروعات التعليم على الماكينات
deep learning projects for a personalized shopping app.
والتعليم المتعمق لأجل تطبيق شخصي للتسوق.
Now, she is here to teach you all about working with data in Python. Enjoy.
إنها هنا الآن لتعلِّمكم كل ما يتعلق بالعمل على البيانات في Python. استمتعوا بالتعلُّم.